

Javad Adib

Engineer & Software Solution Designer

15+ years of experience in programming. Open-source enthusiast. Built the infrastructure of several million dollar projects that are working and gained valuable experience from each of them. Learned how to learn, so just say; Trust me, I'm an engineer;)













+98-935-726-9759



Qom, Iran



MrAdib.com

Experience

Founder, project lead & CEO

libres

Qom, Iran 10/2017 - Present

- Provide cloud infrastructure to 1,000+ businesses, Integrated eCommerce solution with website, app, PoS software, CMS, CRM, accounting software, ticketing system & form builder.
- Overcome hacker attacks by implement a highly efficient web application firewall that detected 100% of attacks.

Full Stack Web Developer & CEO

Ermile

Qom, Iran 7 06/2015 - 12/2019

- Raised \$1M from Angel investor and managed a 15 member cross-functional team to create a Sarshomar that gained about 1M users just a month after launch.
- Built Dash as PHP framework with MVC design pattern and Twig template engine; Developed architecture to A-MVC to reduce complexity & improve flexibility for faster development.
- Constructed the most comprehensive private educational management system in Iran, which serves four organizations, 500,000+ students, and 2,000+ teachers.

Sales Manager and IT Infrastructure Engineer

Novin Security

Noshahr, Iran 7 05/2012 - 12/2013

- Designed and implemented 30+ CCTV security systems and remote monitoring with DVR, Analog, IP Cameras.
- Established a marketing strategy and accelerated sales channels, which increased the company's revenue +70%.

Solution Designer & Full Stack Developer

Freelancer

09/2008 - 06/2015

- Created 40+ WordPress websites and communicated with dozens of customers, including universities, companies, government centers, and celebrities.
- Strengthened negotiation skills and mastered sales skills, optimized speed of 10+ websites, achieved high SEO rank.

Computer Lecturer & University Tutor

Teacher

06/2006 - Lifetime

- Teach thousands of people in various courses about web technologies and ICDL at the University of Tehran, Tarbiat Modares, technical and vocational schools.
- Created and published tens of hours of unique free web and office video tutorials, which has led to the acquisition of skills by thousands of Persian speakers around the world.

Education

M.S. in IT Management

Islamic Azad University - Central Tehran Branch 2015-2022

B.S. in Computer Software Engineering

Islamic Azad University - Nour Branch 2008-2014

Languages

English Fluent C1 **Persian** Native

Volunteer

Full Stack Web Developer

Khadije Charity

Qom, Iran 12/2017 - Present

Made the website and all the software infrastructure and help fulfill the wishes of 110,000+ people.

Software Solutions for Business Expert

WorldSkills IRAN

Tutoring and train for three talent who won silver and two bronze medals in national competitions; Managed the holding of the national team camp to attend WorldSkills 2015.

Skills

Fully Proficient Web Languages HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, PHP

Languages C, C++, C#, VB.NET, Node.js, Shell script, Bash

Web Services SOAP, RESTful APIs, GraphQL

Back-end Template Engine Twig

Databases MySQL, SQL Server

Front-end JS libraries Alpine.js, React, Vue.js, jQuery

Build tools Sass, Grunt, Gulp, Gradle

CSS Frameworks Tailwind, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Materialize

Web Servers Nginx, Apache

Server Configuration Framework and UI cPanel, DirectAdmin

OS Windows, Ubuntu, CentOS, macOS, VMware ESXi

Container Docker, Kubernetes

Microsoft Office Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, VBA Graphic Design Tools Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Figma



Honors & Awards

Membership	Iran
National Elites Foundation	2013
The Best Corporate and Tourism Website 5th Iran Web and Mobile Festival	Iran 2012

Silver Medal Yazd, Iran WorldSkills IRAN - IT Software Solutions for Business 2009

Medallion for Excellence Mashhad, Iran

WorldSkills IRAN - IT Software Applications 2008